[Music]
Hey Rohit, how are you doing? Yeah, I'm
fine. How are you? Yes, very very good.
Oh, sorry. What' you say? Seeing after a
long time. Yeah. Nice. Yeah. Yeah. Yeah.
Yeah. Absolutely. Um well I think the
community is all really really excited
uh to see uh what you have to present
today. Um a quick a quick note actually
in our newsletter where we present all
the tools uh create MVP as part of like
last week's batch of like new tools was
the most clicked on link. Just wanted to
to to share that stat with you. So um
yeah like I think there's definitely
interest um and so yeah uh ready to kick
this off when you are. Definitely. So
yeah uh hello everyone. So I'm Rohit and
uh as uh B mentioned I'm the creator of
create MVP but I also do a lot of stuff
around DeLel and cloud and AI stuff. So
so uh there is some backstory about
create MVP right. So actually this is
the tool I created uh without any plan.
So I didn't wanted to create it. uh it
was just like I I use this structured
format for my cursor then replete and
whatever tools are available there to
create idea to prototype right so I
thought like why not to create some app
which provide this documentation which I
create for my cursor and uh and then
give it to audience so they can actually
create it so that's why we are this is
the open source tool uh completely
available code is public so anyone can
go contribute so Yeah. So today what we
will be exploring is like how to bridge
the gap between this vague ideas which
you provide as a prompt in the any
applications which you which are there
for the idea to prototype and difference
between the vague ideas as well as
functional AI generated code. So what is
the common frustration for your AI
coding tools when you're going through
it right it often struggle with
unstructured prompts. uh let's say like
uh it's means like this tools will
definitely boost your speed and stuff
but uh it doesn't know that much of the
architecture vision so it doesn't know
it it can give you the initial start but
in sometime it will fail to give you the
output because uh this much knowledge it
has only because uh AI this kind of a
models which are available there like
clots on it and all uh this these models
were not created to uh write a code for
they were created to make it
understanding have the real real world
experience do the research and stuff. Uh
so yeah so that is the lack of the
context you provide to this tool. So
that's why it is not developing what you
uh expected and the planning that you
must naturally bring with the
development right. So
uh yeah so that is the questions
mentioned here. So first thing which is
like it is poor knowledge about
architectural decisions uh contextual
intelligence then there's a core quality
often it has like uh like incomplete
information which you have not provided
then outdated information because you
have not provided the updated docs which
are available let's say you are using
nextjs for your code right and there is
something which is newly developed and
you have not provided that inside your
context so that is something which makes
a
And definitely security is one of the
issues right. So for the security thing
you can uh check my previous talks at
cubecon and stuff. So I have given lot
of talks around security AI and all. So
there's always 7030 problem because 70%
code AI can generally write across your
projects you do but 30% you are like
frustrating manual efforts and all. So
yeah so that's where we are like what we
can do and all. So this is the create
MVP. This app is uh provide you
different different files which will
help you to define instructions and all.
Uh there's demo available publicly. So
it creates this different different
files like for the cursor it provides
cursor rules. Cursor rules are
deprecated by cursor now. So it will not
help that much but it is good to have
it. Back end flow front end PD
requirement status text. So all of these
files are very important. Why? I will
show you quickly. So once you provide it
then AI know what to do uh what process
to follow. So the detailed plan it will
be there then more the uh your output
will be smoother and uh designed really
well. So these are the blueprints
created by well structured prompting for
the Gemini 2.5 pro which is the recent
new model. uh we are using that in this
and uh like in just uh I guess two weeks
we received thousand plus users and it
is growing like anything I didn't
expected to it to grow that this much
but yeah uh it was one of the fun
project so that's what we are doing and
I would like to show you why actually so
yesterday I did this cursor uh I it's
just 21 hours right I I guess I you can
see my screen yeah So 24 hours I uh I
did this post on Reddit and you can see
like there is different different uh uh
documentation I mentioned and depending
on the upwards you know
like you can understand this will
actually help the people so that's why
people are actually uh going and uh
asking for it because you will see like
how frustrated people are that like my
cursor agent behaves kind of a dumb in
so many ways like I carefully build my
prompt uh give clear context and all So
this is like natural thing happening
with all of the people right available
there. So if I see the full discussion
uh in the when I posted this uh I had
given the brief like how actually you
can use this AI blueprint approach which
I provide and uh we are not mentioning
create MVP because we are just there to
guide people like what they can do. So
PD is nothing but like you have to
define what who or problem and your
project scope inside this. Then
application flow like what should be the
application flow of your project like
how it should grow. Uh uh let me zoom in
a
little. I guess you can see it. Yeah.
Then text is nothing but which uh tools
to use, which are the best tools
available. Then APIs and stuff. Then
there is a visual language, right? Color
palette and what kind of colors to use,
pastings and all. So if you do this
manually you have to give like uh see I
when I was doing it manually I have to
give like 150 plus clear distinct state
for building the app. So if you do that
then it is like long time you are just
writing the stuff and then but once you
do it it will actually help you to
reduce lot of work. So project status is
one of the thing like uh understand it
like a project sprints which manager
does for your teams in the company
right. So this is the project status
file. So this will have this will have
like uh entire structure of your project
pipeline like what to follow what time
you have to complete this thing and all.
So every time give the instructions to
the cursor or any tool you are using
like uh keep the track of the status as
well as this the requirement file
because we have created in this manner
like this requirement file is there uh
you have to follow it and you don't have
to go outside it. If you go outside it
then you will break my code. Uh uh so
that is the one thing. So the code is
completely open source. So you can go
check it out. Uh it is available there.
Uh so this is how the website looks. So
if you want to do it uh then it is
simple like uh it is one of mean like
why I say the first opensource tool
because I didn't saw any opensource tool
for the PR generated when I created it.
So you can actually uh use this to
create any structured document and
blueprint which AI needs. So as I show
different different requirements and all
and you can easily use this tool with
any of the AI tools like cursor chat GPD
claw and all uh you can use the MCPS of
context 7 inside the cursor and use this
documentation side by side. So you just
have to give this uh generate a habit
tracking app with a uh I'm just giving
it a normal prompt because I wanted it
wanted to create this as a next project.
So
uh generate implementation plan when you
click it it will plan the architecture
it will click uh create one all of this
file one by one and naturally uh as it
is Gemini 2.5 pro with like uh really
high context window which I am giving it
takes lot of time uh around 2 minutes or
3 minutes but definitely you can uh I
have already given this prompt uh as you
can see here uh it took me 3 minutes so
once it is
It generates different different files.
So you don't have to do it manually
right markdown this uh pages markdown
files are automatically created and this
project status and all which I just uh
informed you what it does and all. So
actually one of the uh important file is
this PRD file. As you can see here it
gives the entire structure of the file
like what what our product will be that
it is saying habit quest then what will
be the business goal what will be the
description goals and what what as a
user what should be the instructions and
what should be the process dashboard and
stuff right so if you copy this you can
directly paste it in any tools like
lovable then bold new and all so uh to
give you some uh little brief If like
let's say this is the lovable and then
so in deox UK I gave the similar talk
with the tessle team. So we created this
two uh two kind of a website. So as you
can see this is the website uh I created
just by prompt right this website you
will see in the lovable it just has like
create your imagination and these are
the different different uh stuff it does
but it is not clickable it doesn't do
anything but with uh PR generated by our
tool uh we got this entire dream into
pixels kind of architecture and you will
see it actually defined login sign up
and everything by its own So this is
really quicker right? Uh it solves lot
of question for us. It actually define
credits and all. So it actually created
that backend flow uh very effectively
than uh when you are giving the normal
vague prompt which is like create an app
for text to image right. So this is the
one thing then one of the challenge
which we regularly see in the uh like
bold new and this kind of apps right. So
in the bold new uh this is the tool I
wanted to create like AI thumbnail
overlays I wanted to add in YouTube
videos. So I don't have to watch the
video right. So I can just directly go
and uh
uh get like alcohol warning because I
don't drink so I can get alcohol warning
and I can see like I don't want to watch
this video. Similarly it can for vegan
people and all. So I wanted to create it
but when I uh when I created it at the
start it was going nice but after some
problem I was getting this uh repeated
attempt fix. So I'm doing attempt fix
every time and every time it says like
uh I guess we have fixed it but nothing
fixes. So this is like completely normal
kind of a behavior because there is a
way uh the this prompts work and it will
have some problems that there. So you
can actually use this in different
different any any kind of a tool
available there. You don't have to uh
doesn't have to worry about it because
in in uh AI studio you can actually give
the entire folder but uh let's say we
copied this prompt. So uh we have given
this for like last time which we did but
let's say uh I I I have downloaded this
plan right. So once I download it uh
yeah we can actually use in in the chat
GPD we can use in the claw let me show
uh here. So if you do in the cloud which
is not any idea to prototype app right.
Uh so this actually uses the artifacts.
So here also you can get a little gist
of like what uh our PD can do. But other
than that, so what I was mentioning in
the
cursor. So this is the instruction f
file right which we created and I have
added that instruction folder here. Uh
as you can see for a habit tracking app
and uh so prd uh which is our habit
quest and uh there is like requirement.
So requirement is a file which defines
the purpose, goal and target use
functional requirement. So every time
you are doing something uh so whenever
you are defining the first time uh you
are defining your uh application you
have to give this kind of a prompt like
follow this to create an app and
maintain the flow. Uh similarly I want
to check for the status. So every time
uh once you do it uh every time you have
to cue that uh uh tracking for the
requirements status like follow this
kind of a flow and all. So yeah uh you
can use any kind of a models which are
available in the cursor. So similarly
you will see uh in here different
different functional requirements are
defined automatically. So it will follow
that requirement every time to check
like where are we going good and not and
similarly status status is there right.
So these are the different status and
all. So yeah definitely I would
recommend you to use like sonet uh 3.7
and this kind of a model because they
are meant to be uh really good in this
way. So I was using the auto so that's
why it doesn't give the out output in
manner but yeah so cloud also you can
see system overview it give to us uh
like entire system overview it it gave
us to like user authentication then
habit management and all of this just by
prd the prd which created by our tool
right so you don't have to use the
create mvp if you want you can define
this uh files on your own because you
know the tool really well uh what you
want to create. So if you define that
really well then uh your cursor and this
kind of tools will understand uh really
well. Uh okay. So as you can see it is
creating this Mac directory it created
text to image app. Then config
controllers middleware models everything
it is created by its own. And you can
try this without any uh predefined kind
of a instruction folder. If you do that
then uh you will see it will just create
the create image back and slowly it will
start uh doing that npm installs and
all. But now it knows what to do because
we have given in the instruction uh
front end and uh text tag and back end
like very much detailed you will see
there is like around uh how many lines
582 lines kind of a front end we have
given uh because it is Gemini 2.5 pro
power which is really advanced model I
would say and one of the best model
available now so yeah that's what I
wanted to show you here but uh
definitely if you want to go ahead. I
will also give this uh final output in
the link so you can actually follow uh
like what is developed and all and uh so
hope that hope that helps and also if
you have any questions you can add in
the comments I would love to answer them
uh let me share you the link I guess it
is available uh everywhere so you can
definitely go and check it out but
meanwhile we can when when I'm answering
the questions we can just go like how it
works
Thank you so much Roit. Um yeah, good
good to see this this project live and
and seeing how the workflow uh is. So,
we do have a question uh from somebody
who I think you may know, Jay Sadana. Uh
and he was just wondering whether or not
um you could develop a little bit more
of like when leveraging this sort of
like workflow. Um how do you prevent
like um your previous code to become
stale artifacts or in other words like
how do you continually integrate it with
your continuous delivery pipelines? Uh
can you give us some on this? Yeah.
Yeah. So let's say now this app is
development uh going in development
right. So let's say it is it is going
there uh it is developing some app and
and I uh now cursor started
hallucinating it goes like uh I don't
want to follow you. I will do my own
thing. It will go and create some files
which you don't want to create. Right?
So then that time you have to cue like
uh add requirements uh and this
status like follow this uh follow this
two files and see uh are we on track. I
just say like are we on track but you
can say like are we are we following the
plan? Uh if not please uh stick to my
plan and if you think there is any uh
changes you want to do which is good and
will be better for our plan uh our
project then definitely create one uh
new file inside the instruction and give
it like I want to do like changes md or
this file will be created by cursor and
it will say to us like yeah I want to do
this kind of a changes please
help so that kind of you can maintain
Yeah. Yeah. I think there's always like
a very fine balance between making sure
uh the LLM sticks to the script and the
requirements versus like then when it
goes it completely hallucinates. Um but
uh yeah thank you so much for for this
wonderful session like really really
insightful as I mentioned like uh on our
side we've seen interest with create MVP
so uh it's a very interesting project
and I think uh uh we're excited to see
the traction of it in the future. So,
thank you so much uh for for joining us,
Rohit. Thank you. Thank you. Hope this
helps.